Summary

4-5 years experience with data engineer and soft engineer. (Distributed Queue System, Database, Web Crawling, RESTful API, ETL, Docker, CICD, GCP, Airflow ...etc.)

1-2 years experience with data science. (Data Analysis, Machine Learning and Deep Learning) Github project get 1,600 stars.

Work Experience

17 LIVE - Senior Data Engineer

May. 2021 - Now

- The main developer for refactor ETL. Creating a airflow project by **Cloud Composer** to transfer ETL tools from digdag to airflow and transfer ETL develop method from shell script to python. (More than 20 large pipelines.)
- Maintenance **BigQuery** more than 300 tables and more than 10 TB data.
- Create pipelines from backend team, multiple mysql and mongodb, and appsflyer to bigquery.
- Create a **good development culture**, including the introduction of CICD, dev-stage-master, unit tests and test coverage.
- Create document culture by **confluence**.
- Using Airflow unified scheduler job, like cloud function scheduler, bq scheduler, crontab, and ML model by R or Python ...etc.
- The finalists of **Break the Norm** awards on 2021-Q3 and 2021-Q4.
- Assist in **interview** more than 10 new data engineer.
- Mentor junior data engineers to be more effective individual contributors.

SinoPac Holdings - Software Engineer

Nov. 2019 - May. 2021

- Develop **python**, **C**# api for stock/option/future trading.
- Setup CI/CD with github actions and gitlab-ci to publish package and unit testing.
- Deploy a test system to simulate trading.
- Collecting distributed system log by elk, grafana and prometheus, 13 GB log data/day.
- System monitor of api latency, worker alive and user request count by telegram bot.
- Develop transaction-by-trade and odd lot trading API.

Openup Speaker (**FinMind**)

2019-12-01

Tripresso - Data Engineer Oct. 2018 - Oct. 2019

- Analysis travel data and build a machine learning model. Estimating increase 3% orders (revenue).
- Maintain and develop an distributed queuing system for web crawling with 20 machines.
- Optimize the ETL system reduced more than **50**% execution time.
- Develop new product crawler let product volume increase 1.5%.
- Making **BI charts** provide for other departments.

Publications

• Published a book related to data engineering. Python 大數據專案 X 工程 X 產品資料工程師的升級攻略. On major platforms, like tenlong, books, momoshop ...etc, the weekly sales are the highest TOP 1, and the monthly sales are the highest TOP 2.

Projects

FinMind python project

1,700 Stars On Github. Sep. 2017 - Now

- 3 team member.
- Create a payment flow by ECPay, and getting some order from user.

- More than 2,000 people registered.
- Open source of financial data, more than 50 dataset, more than 1 billion, 200GB.
- 10 million data per day.
- Deploy restful api, backend, web, crawler, rabbitmq, mysql, dolphindb, redis and loading balance by docker swarm and traefik.
- Transfer dataset from mysql to dolphindb, reduce 80% (150GB) data size.
- Using scheduler to automatic update data by airflow, rabbitmq and celery (8 cloud machines).
- Automated deployment web, backend and api by CI/CD.
- Using vue, python and django to develop web pages. (https://finmindtrade.com/).
- The API has more than **100,000** requests per day. Upper bound of api is **8,000/minute** request by ApacheBench.
- Design data pipeline for crawler, backend and analysis by **airflow**.

Bosch Production Line Performance (Kaggle) Grupo Bimbo Inventory Demand (Kaggle) Instacart Market Basket Analysis (Kaggle) Post-competition analysis, top 6% rank.
Post-competition analysis, top 8% rank.
Final top 25% rank.

Education

National Dong Hwa University (GPA: 3.87)

Master of Science, Sep. 2017. Major: Mathematics and Statistics. **Tamkang University**

Bachelor of Science, Sep. 2015.

Major : Mathematics.